Mss.Ms.Coll.95 Mss.Ms.Coll.95
American Philosophical Society
- Series VII. Audio Materials (Box 229-240)
  - Digital Recordings
    - Derived from Sound tape reels
      - Tuscarora Reel, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Reels.23; 2.0 Reel(s)
        - Unidentified Tuscarora story, Circa 1952; Tuscarora Reel-01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:24; Gansworth, Nellie; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Originally recorded on wire, then transfered to sound tape reels. Recording runs slightly fast.
          Tuscarora language; Tuscarora Nation Reservation (N.Y.)
        - Unidentified Tuscarora story, Circa 1952; Tuscarora Reel-01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:19; Gansworth, Nellie; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Unidentified Tuscarora story, Circa 1952; Tuscarora Reel-01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:45; Gansworth, Nellie; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Grammatical elicitation, Circa 1952; Tuscarora Reel-01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:31; Gansworth, Nellie; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Grammatical elicitation, Circa 1952; Tuscarora Reel-02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:50; Gansworth, Nellie; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
      - Umatina Reel, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Reels.24; 1.0 Reel(s)
      - Ute: Jorgensen, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Reels.25; 1.0 Reel(s)
        - Monologue in Northern Ute and English, Circa 1960; Ute: Jorgensen-01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:01; Johnson, Harriet; Jorgensen, Joseph G.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          This program begins as an elicited word list, and turns into a monologue by the speaker, giving miscellaneous improvised sentences alternately in Northern Ute and English. Supplementary information can be found in the Joseph G. Jorgensen correspondence file in the Floyd Lounsbury papers. Significant background hum throughout recording.
          Utah; Ute Indians--Social life and customs; Ute language
      - White Dog Ceremony, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Reels.26; 1.0 Reel(s)
        - Feast of the White Dog (Guy-wee-oo), 1956; White Dog Ceremony-01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:25; Langton, Baden; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Thomas, David
          Solo recitation by David Thomas, firekeeper, and group chants with various participants in the Longhouse. Recorded by Baden Langton at the Six Nations Reservation in the winter of 1956. A letter from Langton to Lounsbury was enclosed in the original tape box. A small strip of paper is taped to the tape reel, on which is typed "CHMI NEWS #23."
          Onondaga Indians--Music; Onondaga Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Six Nations Indian Reserve No. 40 (Ont.)
      - Yucatec Maya, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Reels.27; 1.0 Reel(s)
    - Derived from Wire Recordings
      - Bakairi Stories, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.1; 1.0 item
      - Bakairi Words and Phrases, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.2; 1.0 item
      - Bororo, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.3; 3.0 Item(s)
      - Gillespie: Wyandot, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.4; 1.0 item
        - Elicitation of Wyandot words and phrases, 1950; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:16; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Young, Norman
          This program was made as part of a wire recording sent to Floyd Lounsbury by John W. Gillespie, containing recordings made by himself and excerpts of other field recordings he had acquired. Also see the John W. Gillespie correspondence in the Floyd Lounsbury papers.
          This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Wire recording) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
          Delaware County (Okla.); Wyandot language
        - Elicitation of Seneca words and phrases, 1950; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:49; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Young, Norman
          Delaware County (Okla.); Seneca language
        - Wyandot song, 1950; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:14; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Young, Norman
          Delaware County (Okla.); Wyandot Indians--Music
        - Report on classification of recorded Seneca vocabulary, 1950; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:52; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Discusses the similarity of Seneca and Cayuga, and possible future work on Wyandot. This program was made as part of a wire recording sent to Floyd Lounsbury by John W. Gillespie, containing recordings made by himself and excerpts of other field recordings he had acquired. Also see the John W. Gillespie correspondence in the Floyd Lounsbury papers.
          Cayuga language; Oklahoma; Seneca language
        - Cherokee Marching-In Song, 1950; 1939; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:24; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Owl, Della; West Long, Will
          Recorded off of a played-back phonograph recording originally made in 1939. This program was made as part of a wire recording sent to Floyd Lounsbury by John W. Gillespie, containing recordings made by himself and excerpts of other field recordings he had acquired. Also see the John W. Gillespie correspondence in the Floyd Lounsbury papers.
          Cherokee (N.C.); Cherokee dance; Cherokee Indians--Music; Oklahoma
        - Cherokee Mask Dance, 1950; 1946; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:47; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Moser, Artus; West Long, Will
          Recorded off of a played-back phonograph recording originally made in 1946. This program was made as part of a wire recording sent to Floyd Lounsbury by John W. Gillespie, containing recordings made by himself and excerpts of other field recordings he had acquired. There is a 15-second blank section on the recording, beginning at approximately 2:47. Also see the John W. Gillespie correspondence in the Floyd Lounsbury papers.
        - Cherokee Chants, 1950; 1949-12-04; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:49; Gillespie, John W.; Lossy, Dave; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Recorded off of a played-back phonograph recording, which itself is a re-recording from an original wire recording. Also see the John W. Gillespie correspondence in the Floyd Lounsbury papers.
        - Eagle Dance, 1950; 1946; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:35; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Moser, Artus
          Recorded off of a played-back phonograph recording originally made in 1946. This program was made as part of a wire recording sent to Floyd Lounsbury by John W. Gillespie, containing recordings made by himself and excerpts of other field recordings he had acquired. Also see the John W. Gillespie correspondence in the Floyd Lounsbury papers.
        - Cherokee Cornplanting Dance, 1950; 1949-10-08; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:48; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Recorded off of a played-back phonograph recording originally made in 1949. This program was made as part of a wire recording sent to Floyd Lounsbury by John W. Gillespie, containing recordings made by himself and excerpts of other field recordings he had acquired. Also see the John W. Gillespie correspondence in the Floyd Lounsbury papers.
        - Cherokee Ball Game Dance, 1950; 1939; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:51; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Owl, Della; West Long, Will
        - Cherokee Bear Dance, 1950; 1949-12-04; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:37; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Cherokee Bear Dance, 1950; 1949-10-08; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:09; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Comments on Cherokee dance, 1950; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:24; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          General comments on features of Cherokee dance and possible relationships to Iroquois dance and that of other nothern tribes. This program was made as part of a wire recording sent to Floyd Lounsbury by John W. Gillespie, containing recordings made by himself and excerpts of other field recordings he had acquired. Also see the John W. Gillespie correspondence in the Floyd Lounsbury papers.
          Cherokee dance; Cherokee Indians--Music; Oklahoma
        - Cherokee Friendship Dance, 1950; 1949-10-08; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:34; George, Jack; Gillespie, John W.; Lossy, Dave; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Moser, Artus; Standing Bear, Carl
        - Comments on Cherokee and Eskimo recordings, 1950; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:24; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Discusses available Cherokee recordings, difficulties surrounding making new recordings, and details on subsequent Eskimo recordings. This program was made as part of a wire recording sent to Floyd Lounsbury by John W. Gillespie, containing recordings made by himself and excerpts of other field recordings he had acquired. Also see the John W. Gillespie correspondence in the Floyd Lounsbury papers.
          Cherokee dance; Cherokee Indians--Music; Eskimos--Music; Oklahoma
        - Eskimo Inspirational Song, 1950; circa 1947; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:11; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; McCloud, Red
          Recorded off of a played-back phonograph recording originally made in 1947 or 1948 by Red McCloud. Poor sound quality. This program was made as part of a wire recording sent to Floyd Lounsbury by John W. Gillespie, containing recordings made by himself and excerpts of other field recordings he had acquired. Also see the John W. Gillespie correspondence in the Floyd Lounsbury papers.
          Aklavik (N.W.T.); Eskimos--Music; Oklahoma
        - Eskimo Song, 1950; circa 1947; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:42; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; McCloud, Red
        - Gwich'in Social Dance, 1950; circa 1947; Gillespie: Wyandot-01-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:32; Gillespie, John W.; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; McCloud, Red
          Aklavik (N.W.T.); Gwich'in Indians--Music; Oklahoma
      - LaMere: Winnebago, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.5; 1.0 item
        - Self-introduction, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:12; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          The speed of the recording is uneven and occasionally fast.
          Milwaukee (Wis.); Winnebago Indians--Music
        - Introduction to War Chant, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:01; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - War Chant, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:11; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - War Party Dance Song, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - War Chant, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:59; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Dance Chant, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:56; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Medicine Dance, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:19; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Winnebago Dance, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:23; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Shooting Song, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:56; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Drum Moving Ceremony, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:22; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Buffalo Dance, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:27; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Victory Dance, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:47; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Drinking Song, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:26; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Drinking songs; Milwaukee (Wis.); Winnebago Indians--Music
        - Moccasin Game Chant, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:43; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Lord's Prayer, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:35; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Lord's Prayer; Milwaukee (Wis.); Peyote songs; Winnebago Indians--Music
        - Peyote Song, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:34; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Milwaukee (Wis.); Peyote songs; Winnebago Indians--Music
        - Squaw Dance, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:58; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Lord's Prayer, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:27; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Song with introduction in Winnebago, 1950-12-21; LaMere: Winnebago-01-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:40; LaMere, George; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Oneida text, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.8; 1.0 item
          - Reading of an unidentified Oneida text, circa 1940s; Oneida text-01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:17; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
            A reading of an unidentified Oneida text, repeating the pronunciation of Oneida syllables, words, and sentences. The text may come from those recorded as part of the Oneida Language and Folklore Project, funded by the WPA from 1938-1941.
          - Measurements of Tiwanaku statues, circa 1940s; Oneida text-01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:10; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
            Measurements of numbered Tiwaniku statues given by an unidentified speaker.
            Archaeology--Peru; Tiwanaku culture
          - Message to Floyd Lounsbury, circa 1940s; Oneida text-01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:24; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
            A message given by an unidentified speaker to an unidentified recipient, mostly likely Floyd Lounsbury.
            Archaeology--Peru
      - Micmac, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.6; 1.0 item
      - Mohawk, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.7; 9.0 Item(s)
      - Oneida Wires, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.9; 3.0 items
        - Introduction in Oneida and English, 1939; Oneida Wires-01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:42; Archiquette, Oscar; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Recorded as part of the Oneida Language and Folklore Project, funded by the Works Progress Administration (WPA) from 1938-1941, begun by Morris Swadesh and taken over by Floyd Lounsbury in 1939. This hymn's numbering comes from the Oneida Hymnal, which was assembed as part of this project, a typescript version of whcih is available in the Floyd Lounsbury papers.
          Hymns; Oneida (Wisc.); Oneida Indians--Music; Oneida Indians--Wisconsin; United States. Works Progress Administration
        - Hymn 15: Ja tga to, 1939; Oneida Wires-01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:54; Archiquette, Oscar; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Hymn 1: Whosoever Will May Come, 1939; Oneida Wires-01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:49; Archiquette, Oscar; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Speeches in Oneida, 1939; Oneida Wires-01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:09; Archiquette, Oscar; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Recorded as part of the Oneida Language and Folklore Project, funded by the Works Progress Administration (WPA) from 1938-1941, begun by Morris Swadesh and taken over by Floyd Lounsbury in 1939.
          Oneida (Wisc.); Oneida Indians--Wisconsin; Oneida language; Oral history; United States. Works Progress Administration
        - Speech in Oneida, 1939; Oneida Wires-01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:01; Archiquette, Oscar; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Speech in Oneida, 1939; Oneida Wires-01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:42:22; Archiquette, Oscar; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Speech in Oneida, 1939; Oneida Wires-02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:18:17; Archiquette, Oscar; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Speech in Oneida, 1939; Oneida Wires-02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:20; Archiquette, Oscar; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Speech in Oneida, 1939; Oneida Wires-03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:07; Archiquette, Oscar; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Hymn 18: Must I go empty-handed, 1939; Oneida Wires-03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:42; Archiquette, Oscar; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
      - Paressi, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.10; 1.0 item
      - Quechua, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.11; 1.0 item
      - Quechua Notes, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.12; 1.0 item
      - Seneca, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.13; 1.0 item
        - Unidentified Seneca story, Circa 1950; Seneca-01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:23; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Seneca Indians; Seneca language
        - Unidentified Seneca story, Circa 1950; Seneca-01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:33; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Unidentified Seneca story, Circa 1950; Seneca-01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:42; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Unidentified Seneca story, Circa 1950; Seneca-01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:35; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Unidentified Seneca story, Circa 1950; Seneca-01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:02; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Unidentified Seneca story, Circa 1950; Seneca-01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:55; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Unidentified Seneca story, Circa 1950; Seneca-01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:56; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Elicitation of Onondaga sentences, Circa 1950; Seneca-01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:14:43; George, Lucenda; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Lukoff, Fred
          Elicitation of miscellaneous Onondaga phrases and sentences, recorded and conducted by Fred Lukoff with consultant Lucenda George. This program may have been recorded over a prior recording of an Iroquois Condolence Ceremony.
          Onondaga language
      - Terena-Guarani, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.14; 3.0 items
        - Capitulo 14 de São João, 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:05; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Peixoto, Laura
          Program runs fast.
          Bible. N.T. John XIV; Mato Grosso do Sul (Brazil: State)
        - Swedish speech, 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:42; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Ohrstrom, Sven
          Mato Grosso do Sul (Brazil: State); Swedish language
        - Portuguese speech, 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:24; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Rubens
          Mato Grosso do Sul (Brazil: State); Portuguese language
        - English conversation, 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:25; Horton, Thomas, Mrs.; Horton, Thomas; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Conversation; English language; Mato Grosso do Sul (Brazil: State)
        - El Pantanale del Paraguay (Guarani), 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:49; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Ohrstrom, Rosa
          Mato Grosso do Sul (Brazil: State); Pantanal
        - La Guerra entre el Brazil y el Paraguay (Guarani), 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:53; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Ohrstrom, Rosa
          Mato Grosso do Sul (Brazil: State); Paraguayan War, 1865-1870
        - El Pantalone del Paraguay (Spanish), 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:56; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Ohrstrom, Rosa
        - La Guerra entre el Brazil y el Paraguay (Spanish), 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:49; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Ohrstrom, Rosa
        - Viagem a Limão Verde, 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:40; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Massi, Angelo
          Aldeia Bananal (Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil); Terena Indians
        - História da Minha Vida, 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:14; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Massi, Angelo
          Aldeia Bananal (Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil); Autobiography; Terena Indians
        - Davé e Goliá, 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:31; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Massi, Angelo
          Aldeia Bananal (Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil); David, King of Israel.; Goliath (Biblical giant)
        - Jesus e os Doutores da Lei, 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:48; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Massi, Angelo
          Aldeia Bananal (Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil); Bible. N.T. Luke II, 41-52
        - Saudades do Paraguay, 1950; Terena-Guarani-01-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:05; de Souza, Pedro Coelho; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Program runs very fast.
          Guarani Indians; Mato Grosso do Sul (Brazil: State); Paraguay
        - Tupí e Guaraní, 1950; Terena-Guarani-02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:32; de Souza, Pedro Coelho; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Story of the Guaraní creator, Tupí, and the creation of the Guaraní people.
          Guarani Indians; Guarani mythology; Mato Grosso do Sul (Brazil: State)
        - A Virgem de Ca'acupé, 1950; Terena-Guarani-02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:12; de Souza, Pedro Coelho; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Caacupé, Virgen Colorada de; Catholic Church--Paraguay--History; Mato Grosso do Sul (Brazil: State)
        - Cumprimentos etc, 1950; Terena-Guarani-02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:22; Jordano, Francisco; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
          Portuguese speech about recording languages in Mato Grosso and its benefits, giving well-wishes to Floyd Lounsbury on his work.
          Indians of South America--Brazil--Languages; Indians of South America--Brazil--Mato Grosso (State); Indians of South America--Brazil--Mato Grosso do Sul (State); Mato Grosso do Sul (Brazil: State)
        - Jesus e Mulher de Jerico, 1950; Terena-Guarani-02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:27; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Massi, Angelo
          Aldeia Bananal (Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil); Bible; Jesus Christ; Rahab (Biblical figure)
        - História da Missão, 1950; Terena-Guarani-02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:51; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Massi, Angelo
          Aldeia Bananal (Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil); Catholic Church--Missions--Brazil; Terena Indians--History
        - Grammatical elicitation, 1950; Terena-Guarani-03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:48; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; Massi, Angelo
          Aldeia Bananal (Mato Grosso do Sul, Brazil); Terena language
      - Tuscarora wire, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.15; 1.0 item
        - Unidentified Tuscarora story, Circa 1952; Tuscarora wire-01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:00; Gansworth, Nellie; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Unidentified Tuscarora story, Circa 1952; Tuscarora wire-01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:57; Gansworth, Nellie; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Unidentified Tuscarora story, Circa 1952; Tuscarora wire-01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:55; Gansworth, Nellie; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
        - Unidentified Tuscarora story, Circa 1952; Tuscarora wire-01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:40; Gansworth, Nellie; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn
      - Umatina Translations, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.16; 2.0 Item(s)
      - Umatina Wire, Mss.Ms.Coll.95.Wires.17; 2.0 Item(s)